Hi my name is Lauren and I'm here to talk about how to straighten curly hair. When you are doing your straightening you want to make sure you use first off a hot tool so one of the easiest ways to actually go through and straighten your hair especially when it is very coarse, thick and curly and especially since your hair is a little on the coarser side what is going to happen is it is going to be able to withstand some of the heat from the flat iron You are going to blow out your hair first and use a big paddle brush in order to kind of get it as straight as you possibly can.
After you are done and your hair is dry you are still going to have some curl and maybe a little bit of frizz left in it.
You are going to do smaller sections.
You want to do small sections so that way you can make sure that you get each hair shaft from root to end.
You are going to use a thermal protectant in order to protect your hair from the heat.
It is very important to protect your hair from the heat because you are basically reforming the hydrogen bonds of your hair in order to make it go straight.
You then use a comb and comb through the hair and then follow with the flat iron.
What that does is it helps get any knots out and it helps prevent any creases.
So you are going to put the comb up by the root and then follow it with the flat iron all the way down.
When you are done you are then going to kind of just smooth it.
You are then going to move on to your next section working your way from the bottom up and it makes it a little bit easier.
Again you are going to spray it.
You don't want to take sections that are too big because otherwise you can get lines that are within your hair.
You are going to use your comb to guide your straight iron out because it is going to pull out any of those knots and smooth the hair a little bit for you.
Once you have gone through your entire head and you have now straightened your hair you are going to want to keep it.
The best thing to do is t use some sort of silicone based product.
Silicone coats over your hair cuticle and prevents your hair from absorbing, your cuticle from opening to absorb any water or moisture from the hair.
It will prevent frizz and it will also prevent your hair from going back to its original curl.
Curl needs water in order to strengthen the bond so when your hair is grabbing moisture say if it is a very humid day then your hair is going to automatically start to strengthen its curl bonds and it is going to go back to a wave or some curly.
A silicone based product or some sort of palm aid will help coat over that cuticle and prevent moisture from ruining your perfectly straight hair that you set and that is how to straighten curly hair.